we're not because we just live in echo
chambers on the internet how did the
greatest tool Fred they're like
communicating devolve communication so
much I've been thinking about this a lot
and it's a it's definitely unfortunate
being taken from us yeah it's bad like
we got the Internet and now we just
communicate it really poorly and you
can't emot-- either like make facial
expressions like you can't tell
someone's tone when they're talking to
you so like if you say something
controversial or politically charged and
then somebody makes a comment and you
perceive it as snide if it's like a
question every time somebody else makes
that question you're just gonna assume
that they're being an [__] but maybe
they're just asking a question and this
is like such a big piece of human
interaction that we just lose over the
Internet yeah we have to be able to
trust what the person is saying and
understand what the person is saying I
mean if we're completely having
different conversations and we're
posturing towards every single thing the
other person says they don't actually
get to give me to Kate what they need to
communicate and it's unfortunate it's
really bad it's just not what I want at
all all right well so we will touch back
on that but uh we are in for the
junkyard love podcast Spencer Hicks
welcome aboard again my friend so we've
got Spencer on again today Spencer as
someone who him and I will be having
many conversations regarding I don't
know just the exploration of
consciousness and life and everything
that comes with it and how to take care
of this meat pot as you do so on the way
all these things but so there have one
live conversation with Spencer it's
great I enjoyed it it was awesome but we
actually recorded last week we're gonna
try to do as often as we can once a week
every two weeks whatever but the
conversation went it was total butthole
and we were both text each other
afterwards like hey how're you feeling
on that and we're both like it sucked I
suck let's delete it so what we're doing
here is
the reason why I bring this up is
because no I'm not gonna post it but I
think that the importance of failing out
loud it's something that I want to keep
prattling on this podcast I think just
being honest about like sometimes I'm
not the best host sometimes like I've
only done 15 of these damn things I'm
not a I'm not a podcast so it's like I
don't go to podcast hosting school you
know and and also my guests when they
come on they're not claiming to be
professionals of anything like last time
I I was kind of questioning Spencer as
if I could pay so what can you tell me
about the supplement it's industry you
know like he's some sort of genius about
it and so anyway I just want to round
out that I'm just a DJ audio engineer
person with and I don't know intricate
life with a different aspect that people
seem to like to listen to sometimes so
I'm not claiming to be any expert if my
guests are experts on things I'll
include that in the comments but
otherwise we're just we're just having
conversation and I don't know I get I
just want to clear that Spencer because
I feel like I
last time I kind of put the pressure on
us to like be like okay man first within
the first 10 episodes we got to explain
to people this and then we got to know
they got to know what enlightenment is
and they got to know what supplements
they should take every day and what
morning routine and middle of day
routine and out of day routine and all
the times between we got to make that
all pristine and perfect for everyone so
anyway I'm just don't want to overthink
things so today Spencer and I though we
may touch on some more serious subjects
we are just here to hang out and talk
because Spencer Hicks I love you man and
I'm glad that you're in my life so just
as friendship I appreciate you and I'm
glad to have you here on this
conversation that doesn't really need to
be that complicated yes I love you too
Jacob and I actually would like to touch
on all of those things but what I
learned from failing was that I don't
take myself seriously at all I'm
literally just a guy to think sometimes
and then trying to sit down and just
take yourself really seriously because
like I got to help people like I
information that will be helpful it just
did not like it just as not naturally
how I go about communicating and it felt
very contrived yeah it's funny we do
that to ourselves so we think we're like
oh can you show up as this person but
what you got to do is show up as
you in that situation you don't have to
be a certain type of person to to just
communicate an opinion or communicate
something that you have learned like you
don't have to to give someone a little
bit of info on neuroscience you don't
have to be a neuroscientist
I mean claim where you're at of course
but yeah so anyway man
I'm just glad you a to have the [__]
sesh with you yes of course just a good
banter yeah so let's just see what I can
pull out of my butt to throw at you if
there was a zombie apocalypse at this
moment while we're filming this we get a
little we get a little notification an
Amber Alert on her phone and it says
listen they're zombies everywhere that
shit's real is happening it's probably
gonna reach your town within 10 hours
what's your what's your prospect what
you doing oh we definitely got to go get
enough food to survive so my thing with
of zombies is that so if your body
requires cell your energy they're
eventually all gonna die cuz they
haven't eaten enough after like the
people to zombie ratio wears off so if
we can just wait okay but what about the
ones in I am Legend where they went to
the dark and they seemed to like kind of
hibernate almost right they were like
remember they'd be in those Huddle's did
you watch that one with Wilson didn't
yes I did yeah what would that be those
ones probably eaten alive I think that I
would pretend to be a hero like I'm
close enough to Mount st. Helens that I
would be like I'm gonna drive up there
and I'll solve this and I'll be like I
don't know I'll have like some sort of
essential oils book trying to combine it
with like something I read from Sam
Harris trying to figure out some cure
for cancer we could do the classic get a
pointy stick and find a cave with one
entrance and just caveman it out I mean
that's kind of what we're doing as a
society anyway all right we're just
going right back to the tribalism thing
yes just gotta find a group of people
that you trust a stabs and hee-ho hey in
life if there's one thing you learn from
this podcast it's just find a good
friend Sam zombies with you know if you
really think about it that's how you
should choose your friends like hey this
person like they're cool they have all
these things on social media it's cool
they have a cool car they like this cool
music but if there was a zombie
apocalypse would they be the most
annoying piece of [__] ever would they
suck would they get me killed would they
kill my sister like
you got to think of these things so I
think in life you should probably just
find people you'd be chill with killing
zombies oh yes
like how are their survival adaptations
yeah yeah are they like big and strong
are they gonna get away quick or they're
like gonna eat my food and I'm not
looking so that's why you that's why you
do the bodybuilders you hang out with
you hanging out the gym so there's just
a strangled zombies and find new friends
do that was I honestly anticipated that
I think that I think that honestly if
there was some sort of zombie so even
let's just say there's some sort of like
catastrophic or even like the economy
collapse it's something just to wear
with with there may be some sort of like
brawls or some real surviving that needs
to happen I think that a lot of our a
lot of our society would be incapable
like I don't know how the hell I would
really really like the insaneness of
okay well the world as we know it has
gone like say the internet shut down
electricity shut down we'd be so [__]
helpless dude what we do driving home
from Thanksgiving and I was just like
looking at the window thing about how
fragile society is like all our human
constructs are just so fragile like even
like your own mind and sense of being
like everything involved with us is just
like so close to collapsing so the
inversion curve or yes I think that's
what it is inverted no the yield curve
inverted so it's like signaling that the
stock market's gonna crash it's like who
what like this is just this is a
terrible system that nobody really knows
how to operate unless you're in it and
then we just it could just do not work
all of a sudden every 10 years and then
everyone has to deal with it well and
we're also just like well okay they're
like it's not working like okay like
really they think they're just doing
whatever the [__] they want and we're
just like our strings are being pulled
it's so funny saying that I watched that
explained on Netflix last night we
watched the one on diamonds have you
seen that oh no but I didn't know a lot
about this for me oh do you yeah so
essentially you probably know that it's
like the value of diamonds like the
inflation of these diamonds over these
time it's always think it's all it's all
a marketing you know it's De Beers the
company yes anybody can watch this thing
on this so on there in the 1920s they
actually pushed a huge so they own 95
percent of the diamonds in the world
this one company and diamonds are
intrinsically worthless
they make most of them now yeah now yeah
so they pushed like an engagement ring
advertisement and then they made it a
societal norm to get engagement rings
you have to buy two rings and that
propaganda was so strong that you could
explain this to your significant out
there in the be like yeah it's still
like both please yeah well I mean that's
kind of how it is still I mean we we say
like man that's crazy and then our next
sentence is like yeah I know you can
know all these things you can know the
history of it and like this is obviously
just a scam you're getting scammed out
of money for this rock that's not worth
more than a car but you're still gonna
buy both rings cuz that's societal norms
and that is the most powerful ad
campaign of all time
well here's the thing is is we got a
look at these things so when I first
started like I don't know when I first
started like discovering like oh man
that thought was put there by society
standards or this thing that I do like I
don't really want to do that that's just
you know when I first started I don't
know I guess I guess thinking about all
this stuff it was like I was mad I was
like what the [__] like they're lying to
us all these things but then I don't
know I feel like the more you learn
about the whole thing it's like you
gotta just do what you can in your small
little corner like you're so
insignificant in this whole thing at
first right like you gotta I don't know
I I was so mad but then I was like man I
don't know how I would have run a
society though like what the [__] could
you imagine like all these people who
are here and then you'd be like well we
should probably name steffel so that's a
tree and I'm like what about the ground
connected to it and they're like no no
they're separate like we started naming
things and then we started to have it
have some sort of society and culture
grew into what it was it's just so have
achill and so broad that anyway what we
started talking about with this one
zombies so the society has our brain so
[__] up sorry full circle alright
Society has our brain so [__] up that
we have these levels of like truths in
like thoughts that are so close to just
making us just all insane and dissociate
completely from who we think we are like
that alone just the thoughts but like if
electricity went out and so an internet
went out we wouldn't load we would just
turn into pieces of dust and we
say we would be like Peter Parker just
floating away no man you are you know
how to forge food no I don't I don't
know not even a little bit yeah there's
a gas go to near near my house and they
have you know whatever snacks I need so
you know you know that you're fighting
people at the gas station yeah I'm not
gonna get gassy I'll go there just get
alright well its apocalypse let me just
wait in line to get gas that will happen
for 30 minutes you you see it when like
home sports team wins and everyone just
goes to Ravin as it starts flipping cars
like that's not it's a good thing that
happened think about it something bad
happened people just do just devolve in
decay bends so fast
what's crazy is we we see stuff like
that right so so I so we would see so
okay the example Philly they won the
Super Bowl last year or the year for
whatever was at home I don't want to
support you yeah that's what sports
bought they won the thing and what
happened I get was like that like there
was people going crazy flipping cars
like I don't know if Aris exactly
flipping cars there were just craziness
in the streets and I always flip cars
but we see it and well that's so insane
they're crazy but then we don't see the
same things that we do we're all just a
bunch of crazy ass Apes who when you
give us too much of a certain thing
alcohol excitement crowds loud music
excitement competition more alcohol
whatever like we just we turn into like
just swinging or [__] fists in a
circle we're just like it's so
rambunctious but we don't we kind of see
it as like oh they're crazy doing that
thing but we don't see that us as
individuals we all have our own little
bit of monster a penis that would kind
of have to oh yeah there's a monster
Josiah homeless definitely yeah well you
get that big mob mentality it's like
okay somebody threw a chair oh that's
there's like a garbage on fire and
everyone starts getting riled up then
all of a sudden you're saying on top of
a flipped a burning car while people are
screaming and fighting in the streets
just because your hand egg team won
well crowds are interesting I think this
is something that actually did want to
talk with you Spencer so we have been
both fans of electronic music for a long
time we've been both going to a lot of
like music festivals a lot of concerts a
lot of people call them raves just I
mean that's just that we can we can
cover that we can we can explain that
terminology too but a
I was talking with somebody the other
day and I want to talk to you about it
because as you get older as you you grow
up in the EDM crowd like me as a DJ when
I was younger like 18 or 19 or something
I went to my first show and it was Rusco
and I knew nothing about it but a change
my whole life and so I'm like at that
show I was like hammered
I was front row I wasn't I was bumping
into everybody and for those next two
years I was like rage I would have to
touch everybody which is not like me I
wanted to just like bump into everybody
and just dance around that's what I'm
you might touch everybody meet everyone
getting everyone snapchat right that's
you know but but so anyway so over the
years though so that's when I was a
young kid over the years now I'm 28
I've you know kind of watching from an
aerial view of what I did as I got older
at shows I've always still gone to shows
I go to different ranges of shows but I
still love electronics music festivals
these different things I started like
like I was kind of back farther right
like a few years after rage and I was
upfront I was loving this certain kind
of music and I was kind of backed up a
little bit and I didn't want to be
touched so much I don't want to be in
the mosh pit and I started backing up a
little bit more and so as the years go
on you kind of start to back up from the
crowd of electronic music of the like
I'm saying actually at the shows like
you're farther away from the stage and
now I'm to the point where it's like
giving me a balcony and a beer and a
chair and I will see you know anybody
there's certain times where I'm like
let's just dance if she only wants to
dance to try to get out and dance to you
but and then so I feel like I've kind of
observed all these different sorts of
people because that all these stages of
a crowd there's different people
different personalities there's
different layers right and I think that
honestly mom mentalities are similar
these different layers of people I think
there's a lot of branch of interesting
subjects there but but anyway I'm at the
point now where I've been in the crowd
but I've also been on the reverse of in
DJing of these large crowds and I'm an
observing human I'm a chameleon I like
to fit into wherever I'm at so I feel
like I have like firsthand reporter I
don't know
bird's eye view from every spot in the
crowd of a festival and all these things
so and I feel like you just
you over the years like I feel like you
have slowly probably drifted back
towards with me I feel like maybe you
are always a bit more towards the back
type of person but no I want to talk
about maturing through but but but still
enjoying every second of music in
festivals and then maybe if we if you
want to touch on like the crowd
differences in between so it's funny
because when I got into it I was 18 and
I just became friends with your group of
friends and what your 4 year 5 years
older than I am so what's going with
Tyler and we just stayed in the back I
like I don't like being touched I don't
like people around I like to thrash
around and like have a lot of space and
I don't like people like standing in
front of me I don't like to be jostled I
just want to be left alone sorry but
I've gone up there and it's just
incredibly claustrophobic and I can't
send her in on the music because I want
it being at a concert is actually a very
it's a very social thing but it's
violently intimate because it's just
like you are just looking at this one
person performing and this crowd will
disappear but if I'm constantly being
pulled out of that it will ruin my
experience absolutely I can't focus so I
just like to be in the back but there's
a different dichotomy of people in the
crowd though there's you know I don't
know if it's half and a half but there's
some people who are there to talk to you
and hang out with your friends which
cool awesome there are some people who
are there to just please let me just
stare into this screen space in front of
my eyes for one hour so there's also
that you have to deal with wherever
you're in the crowd yes people get
people go to get belligerent a lot and
those people run the crowds and there's
hard to deal with they're incoherent
they're bumping into you and I was that
guy when I was 17 so I mean so was I for
a little bit I mean because you just get
you just get fun yeah it's super fun cuz
you just get really drunk and then
you're just like are not aware of your
space and there's people egging you on
you bump into a dude and he goes and you
go dude that's like the most we're so
excited to be able to have a place where
we can do that that that's crazy I will
say it was very transformative and who I
am now because it's led me to just not
actually conformed any social norms at
all and just kind of look at everything
and like hey we can do it everyone like
we did we just get to go to this
festival and just be crazy apes for a
while and like dancing
and stomp and just not just like
completely lose all inhibition it's
something that it's gotta be pretty
important obviously through rituals and
stuff you know they've always done it
they've always had I I don't really know
how that how that would work like you
know what what tribes you could say that
did these rituals and dances and stuff
but I know that even at home man there's
some times where I'll just smoke a nice
big J and I'll go in the backyard with
bare feet and just dance around like a
dummy and just kind of do something I've
told you about the Zen swing that I do
move to the cerebral fluid in your spine
which you like to talk about we talked
about it last time but dude it just it
just feels right I feel like it is
although I don't entirely condemn just
getting blacked out drunk and running
around with your fists out at a rave but
there is something that if you super
primitive about it we're like yes this
feels crazy good mm-hmm
and I think so all these like old
rituals like these tribal rituals
there's always a mono tempo banging of
the drums and EDM is like that it's just
very drum heavy it's very rhythmic it's
just the whatever the BPM is there's a
drum line that goes with that and that
goes to every song so you almost get
entranced to these things and like as
the day goes on and you get a little
more tired and like you just slowly boil
down who you are especially it's like
day three of a festival and everyone is
like on autopilot you just get this real
real caveman a behavior reverence like
chanting around doing weird stuff like
it just though you will witness the
weirdest things if you go to an EDM
festival and you're so okay with it oh
it's wonderful oh it's great it makes
you feel very whole I mean I actually
haven't been to Burning Man but I
imagine that Burning Man it's like the
ultimate example of what we're talking
about but there's so many festivals that
it makes you it reminds you of like
what's really going on here in life
really I mean I know a lot of people
like if you don't know much about like
the the EDM rave the scene and you see
it from the outside I get that it looks
insane but it's I mean it kind of is but
it's great oh it's totally it supposed
to be is the thing it's supposed to be
exuberant and loud about it certain
things but it's it's when you're in it
and you let yourself be in it and that's
an important thing going there taking
pictures of people like making fun of
people saying yourself has that's
separate than them being too cool
whatever you don't really get the
experience right
and you're the one losing two if you can
the moment you gotta let go and just
flail around yeah because I think that
when you stop dancing singing enchanting
is when you lose your dear your inner
child right and this is like the
greatest expression of that you just go
with everyone you love to this thing
away from everywhere it's like in the
most beautiful spots you can see the
sunset and you just jump and dance
around thrash your body and I will just
when I've found myself just dancing all
the time now from it and I'm just always
ever since then really like sunk into
music a lot more like I save all my
really aggressive musics that's what I
like the really aggressive EDM just for
the gym and I was like be dancing around
not paying attention anyone and it just
is such a it's a way more enjoyable if
you can just not allow other people and
what they think to rotate what you do
because you will enjoy yourself a lot
more well in the more you do that the
more that it that it trains you to do
that later so like I mean being
self-conscious is huge thing especially
like at shows when you're like kind of
[__] up and you're trying to dance
around but it all sin you have the
self-conscious like me and people are
looking at you you look kind of drunk
and sloppy I mean you're gonna start
getting self-conscious and I have a good
time so training yourself to not care
what other people are doing even if
you're just at the gym even if you're
just waiting in line at the [__] at
the DMV
whatever yeah that's right if you feel
like it and it's great once you once you
get to the point where it's like and
[__] it I just don't care I don't care
what anyone thinks like I'm just gonna
do me and I'm gonna have the best time I
can like it your life is just so much
more enjoyable like that it's like who
gives a [__] what other people think you
don't even know you how are you gonna
let them judge you and infect you you're
defending something that they don't know
about you that they think they know
about you but it's not actually true
what why would you do it the only people
I ever let their opinion affect me is
people that are close to me and that I
also respect because it's like okay You
Know Who I am and if you have something
critical to say I really respect that
but if like Joe with the gym is like hey
why you dancing around well you know eat
[__] Joe like I don't have to tell you
dude she relax Joe at the gym I feel
like inevitably everybody just has
someone in their mind like just popped
in for Joe people are just so rigid just
relax relax that was us last podcast
just all tense
I just wasn't all there though really as
I was just like how I'm being a bad host
and whatever it's so funny we'd do that
to her so I felt uh okay cuz all the
information we're talking about I
actually do understand to a really high
degree but I've never it's always in
small morsels that I get a like leak out
to people like when I'm training like oh
go down this rabbit hole tell them about
like metabolism but to sit down and like
step by step explain all the scientific
research that I'm aware of you know that
I didn't prepare for works I'm like oh I
know this of course I can do this I was
so incredibly overwhelmed it almost felt
like an out-of-body experience
I'm like whoa okay black boiling inside
and we also didn't really get in a
headspace to do it
we had a disruption before critical
failures okay but I I mean I will say
though you didn't fail at anything it's
not like I mean I glanced back through
the conversation it was good it wasn't
exactly what we hadn't wanted but I
think that a lot of times a week we
question if we're the ones who should
know anything we have this imagine if
you're talking about like glycogen
you're going off about it but you kind
of like misstep and you say one thing
incorrectly well someone in the comments
who was a [__] glycogen master is
gonna try to rip you apart or say that
you're an idiot but what I will say that
this space like my podcasts where I'm
trying to put it like on YouTube I have
noticed not the social media thing not
Facebook not Instagram here but the
comments are like hey man thanks for
trying to explain that it seems like you
got a little confused with glycogen and
whatever you know like the the comments
section so I'm it's encouraging I'm
pointing out that it's encouraging
because I think that I don't want to go
through and be deleting a bunch of these
you know I think that like even if we're
[__] up even if I'm not the best host
even if you know like maybe I'm I'm out
of medication that day or you know
whatever I don't know the other person
is maybe I think they're just being
truthful in talking about things that we
do know about and then just having it
open like hey if we messed up where
we're trying to be honest and truthful
just write it in the comments let's have
a conversation or hit me up let's
actually talk more in depth we can even
bring it back up on next podcast but
we're just a couple of [__] dudes but
you are pretty damn smart Spencer I will
say there is many things that we text
about
that are just profound and there's many
things that we do kind of dance around
there there are some others that I think
you would be great at expressing and in
really teaching people so let's say
hovering above the word health mmm-hmm
you're very you're a fit man you're very
healthy I do want people to value my
podcast for their health mentally and
physically is there maybe like some some
broad little information or things that
you want to like dive down and let
people know about health-wise anything
you want to touch on there there's a
couple things I've been really into
lately and it's a stress management
stress management okay what it was what
stress may have been all about what do
you mean so you your master stress
hormone is cortisol and there's a lot of
like we live such a hectic life and we
don't eat very well like there's a lot
of vitamins that will offset this and
like carbohydrates will actually lower
this that's why like when you get really
stressed you want to like panicky or
binge eat carbs because they are a
natural balance to cortisol expression
and not sleeping enough and living too
stressful of a life will cause us to
drive up and then all your body
functions will not work quite as well
your propensity to gain fat is much
higher and you won't lose weight you're
gonna feel tired you're gonna feel very
irritable so just focusing on that and
that's why a mindfulness practice is
great right because it's the perfect
temper to this we our bodies are not
evolved to live the way we do live like
the day to day business lifestyle
quickly no it's just it's too much it's
so overwhelming and people put so much
on their plate that they just have an
extreme stress response all the time and
it's not everyone like you have to state
of being so you have sympathetic and
parasympathetic nervous Tate's
sympathetic is like stress go compete
like very just a high stress very
high-strung people and then
parasympathetic is like mindfulness
eating resting and you really a lot of
people are either one or the other like
I'm very parasympathetic ly driven so it
takes a lot for me to get like excited
hmm so I don't have any problems with
stress but I have the opposite problems
I have a really hard time and doing
stuff and getting up and getting
energy - totally interesting okay okay
so I'm very very very mellow but most
people are not like that
they're very very sympathetically driven
okay so in order to just function
properly you got to drive stress down
and sleeps a really big cornerstone to
that yeah I feel like a lot of people
may get neglect sleep it's something
that I personally man I used to like we
have with the way that our languages
especially with tools like Twitter they
take our our excuses and whatever and
they kind of like alright let's make
that cool let's make that part of my
personality like it's not like I would
always I would make sure everybody knows
and I'm the one who like sucks at
sleeping and I'm always awake I think
that a lot of people have these same
sort of things like team no sleep or
like whatever three coffees a day
whatever kind of weird I think that
sleep I feel a lot better now that I
prioritize sleep I got off the great red
schedule that I was on for six years
seven years which was just ruining my
life
now that I prioritize sleep genuinely I
have to agree with you so much that it's
something that I was like yeah of course
you know kind of brushed it off and then
I would still just get four hours get
five hours and eight hours is too much
for me but like six and a half seven
hours I've learned what works for me and
if I have like a long meditations during
the day I actually can sleep less - so
that's another benefit of meditation if
once you get going not at the beginning
it's a little confusing but once you get
a regular meditation process you
actually need a little less sleep in
some cases but so we talked about sleep
so I guess just just the mental health
when it comes to being that when it
comes to fitness so I think that even
going to the gym when you're just like
at this high anxiety level this this
parasympathetic level or the opposite
that is sympathetic so what can we do so
I know that we both like been pull-up
Polaski polisky pacol ski because CB PAC
pack yeah so he talks about like before
you go to the gym like if you're someone
who's like I need to lose weight I'm so
scared or I need to get healthy whatever
he talks about the first thing you
should do is be able to have a mindful
walk outside and I remember hearing that
when he was talking about that on a
podcast line I think Tim phyleus podcast
and I was like man that is actually very
profoundly something that I wish I would
have told myself when I started my
health workout journey back in the 10th
grade of high school so can we talk a
little bit about
that was what would being able to go for
a mindful walk do for someone trying to
go to the gym well just mindfulness in
general actually does Rebecca just
lowering stress hormones and just kind
of getting into a more parasympathetic
state so let's say you have a bunch of
levers like that will change your body
if you pull them so it's like okay
remove food add training like all of
these things if you you have got a
master lever which is sleep and
mindfulness and like keeping your stress
hormones low and when you don't do that
the other two lovers are not gonna work
when you pull them so your body's just
not gonna respond to any of these things
if you don't just set it right in the
first place so it really does all start
with the centering of the self huh
that's very important yeah it definitely
is so what are you okay so somebody who
yeah that's super true when you go
outside so let's say go outside and go
for a walk before you go to the gym you
go outside and you'll notice that you're
I think walking going for a walk with no
headphones or no music I'm holding it I
think it'll be enough there to realize
like oh maybe I am like a little more
anxious maybe my thoughts are actually
think about all these things and think
about all these things I should do I'm
thinking about why am I going in a walk
I don't have all this time bla bla bla
so just by going on a walk I think is
where you're able to gauge where you're
at at least you can in and you can say
like okay as I'm doing this isn't going
this walk why am I doing this you could
answer these questions for yourself in
your head and you could calm yourself
like okay I am going and walk because
even though life it's crazy I do have
time for this moment I don't have to be
all stressed out right now because I
think that we take that to the gym we
take we're like okay I have an hour I
need to perform for the hour I need to
show up all these things but I think
that the way that an advanced athlete
trains is very very different than the
way a person who just got into gym who's
trying to get healthy or it's just
trying to live a healthy life and trains
yes notable performance isn't inherently
not healthy like there's a slider like
are a spectrum and it's not training
unhealthy and then right in the middle
is like I am training for wellness like
I just want to maintain muscle maintain
my body weight
or even like lose some and just like
just be generally healthier and then you
get to performance where you're trying
to put as much muscle on as possible
will be faster stronger bigger every day
and that is also not healthy not saying
don't do it like if that if this brings
you a very large sense of accomplishment
just to see changes in your body do that
just be aware that there's going to be a
toll that is paid in other places but I
think people when they when they first
start they go off on those journeys
thinking that they need to do one of
those two things mm-hmm well yeah of
course you want to I want to have the
ABS I want to be a big burly man but
well I mean a lot of these things for a
lot of people aren't like quote unquote
possible with the lifestyles they're
living so it's like I want to have all
these things but I also still want to be
able to work my job and enjoy my time
with my dog it might like you can't be
shooting for goals of abs when it
doesn't fit your lifestyle I want to
switch around the lifestyle so I think
it's kind of silly like where I think
that so many people don't know a goddamn
thing about health and who wants to
admit that we know nothing about our own
body that we've been walking around in
for almost thirty years you know in in
we just had a conversation earlier about
you know even the the disadvantage from
young people and old people old people
you know who wants to old people is a
huge generalization here right but old
people who wants to you know listen to
some 20 year old kid who's telling you
about your workout plan or you about
your whatever because everything that
you learned in high school like is
different now and it's not really we've
kind of uncovered some more things about
it I don't know I think that being able
to be told that you're wrong in the
health world is a huge [__] thing
it's a huge thing that needs to happen
yeah I don't know what else what else
can we dance around with in newbies
going into the oh don't get married to
any ideas please dogmatism ruins fitness
no oh I'm Aikido guy who I'm this I'm
that because you have such an individual
biology and genetic makeup that's just
because it looks good and the person
that talks well on the Instagram does
this doesn't mean that's going to work
really well for
you because you have your own behave
identity so if yeah of course if that
works for him you would think it would
work for you but it's not a one-to-one
we're not even close to the same
you're not them and that's fine that's
okay you just need to not get married to
anything and just treat all of this like
a big science experiment
yeah what's right thanks fo yeah small
variables change them okay how did I
respond to this did I respond well okay
let's keep doing that and then slowly
find the foods that like you not the
foods that you like find the exercises
that like you not the ones that you like
and figure out what you what you respond
well to and then what you like do you
think that the way that our society is
we have a little trouble feeling allowed
to analyze herself in such ways like
it's like sometimes I feel like the
doctor is the only one who could tell me
about my health you know what I mean
like if you're not this weight at this
age in your this male or female then
you're not healthy and so we're like oh
well we don't know how to control we
don't know what to shoot for and so we
shoot at these stupid targets I think
that going back to mindfulness going
back to being mindful about your health
and mental health gives you the ability
to say like oh I can assess my own
[__] body like I I think you know
dance around this very carefully and
don't mean naive but I think even
medications I think we take these
medications and we don't know a damn
thing about them we know only what one
person told us about it and we're like
hey what does that do and we say oh no
and you know read the label
it's insane to me I think that we need
to get better at trusting ourselves to
listen to our own bodies in every way
learning about different things like I
mean I know that I can t pick myself
more than a lot of people I don't
suggest that every does that if you
don't have if you have a little fear on
that but I think just trying out what
works for you you know like I worked out
and every about everybody else's ways
for years and years and years and and I
had many fitness goals that I that I met
and that I failed at and I've been
strong I've been fast I've done tons of
like all these races that I really
seriously enjoyed so I don't I don't
like regretting my fitness journey but I
will say in the last year and a half
I've completely flipped it around like I
don't go to the gym anymore because it's
not what works best for me it's not how
I feel the most healthy I mean honestly
the most healthy thing for me seems to
be laying on the carpet doing yoga for
15-minute increments is in between
working on the computer all day so I
think that learning about your body in
every way is one more important things
in mindfulness I would say health of
that yeah you are the proud pilot of a
meet vehicle just like all of us and I
feel like it's everyone's duty to
themselves so just understand one on a
utilitarian level how biology actually
works like you need to just have a
baseline idea of how these things
interact with your body why you're doing
them like everything you do must have
some kind of purpose or goal or you will
never be able to actually see if it's
working like this is a very bad science
experiment if you don't have an end goal
in mind and then also don't let doctors
tell you what's best for you okay like
you have the internet go use it okay no
but but people are gonna hit up the
internet and they're gonna WebMD the
first thing that comes up is going to
tell them they have colon cancer and
they don't be terrified don't do that
actually if you have any fitness
questions message me on Instagram I
promise that what I've tried to do is
have the most nuanced opinion of that
physically can and take everyone into
consideration as much as I possibly
could right because it's it's never a
yes-or-no answer it's always an it
depends answer and you just must try
these things and it would be a shame if
you go through your whole life and you
just never feel like feel what's best
for you you never try the things that
are the best because what if there's
like so you have like a board of buttons
and those are you and you only push a
couple your whole life just pushing a
couple buttons and but you hit like 70
and you push another one you're like oh
that's my favorite button well you
[__] up because you don't brush all
the buttons do it you could hit that at
six-year and that'd be way funnier yeah
go try stuff see what works for you and
failure is not a thing because you learn
something you know I couldn't imagine
not pushing all the buttons I'm such a
button pusher I mean this analogy is
carrying to every single corner of my
life of me as a person but I love just
like I couldn't imagine just not trying
all these things out I think that isn't
it so crazy that we're so it seems like
fear is the word is like scared is the
word right like you know like you and I
are our people
explore our bodies and we learned about
these things like we were just talk
about nootropics but why is it do you
think that so many people are like
scared is that the word I don't know
what you know I'm talking about here
like people really don't want to know
anything about their body it's almost
like the fear of knowing that this thing
can be bad is enough for them to just
completely avoid it yeah but okay it's
comfort it just comes down to comfort we
the d the devil you know was always
better than the one you don't
can we talk about that criminally - like
evolutionary wise can we talk about why
we do that Comfort yeah because why is
Comfort good if you're currently
surviving now what's the what's the
biological incentive to do other stuff
because it could risk your life right so
the caveman brain doesn't want to just
like go out and try a bunch of [__]
because it's like hey we're surviving
now this feels good this is comfortable
yes that's why I like very dogmatic
beliefs are really people love them like
to get really into like vegan is so
[__] dangerous though Oh most
certainly because they are devoid of
nuance yeah and you allow if you allow
an ideology to become a part of you if
people attack it or talk to you about it
it's an attack on you and you're no
longer can see something with nuance
right so if you get oh I'm team this I'm
team that real real deep into these
camps
you just have basically shut yourself
off from any new ideas and that is just
philosophical suicide and you just
should not do that in any facet of life
not even just health and do I mean
noticing that you're doing those things
is like super important it and it's
actually incredibly a lot easier like it
becomes like so that's something that it
you know it's like wait how would you do
that how do you just become more
self-aware what the heck you're doing
and pitching in on other people's ideas
and stuff but just start questioning
everything yeah learning about life
everybody life start questioning
everything why do I do this why do I
take this why do these people do this
like what are their goals one of my
goals like what do I really want like
you need to ask yourself all these
questions and then if you can build a
more concurrent worldview and then
approach health with like a like a
stronger sense of who you are and what
you want you could probably navigate a
lot better because you have more of a
baseline but you must never forget that
new ideas are important and even bad
ideas you must learn from them of course
I mean yeah but
I think that you if you don't have a
target that even exists you're
definitely not gonna hit it you know so
I think that learning learning anything
and just trying it you know try it out
don't don't anything so don't be like I
wonder what steroids are light and like
and just put like a needle into your arm
if they but learn about it
learn about whatever the hell you want
learning about what's gonna work for you
well you have the Internet you gots the
Internet we have unlimited wisdom 90% of
its [__] though so actually learn how to
research yes so second time and being
alive is so complicated with this world
so that's even another step back from
what we were just talking about if you
want to do this then you must do this
then you must do this but before that
you need to learn how to use the
internet so learning how to use the
Internet I will tell you the ultimate
life hack because Yahoo Answers people
are [__] nutty don't get your
information from you who answers people
you gotta read it like an adult that's
oh so if you have what what is a
carbohydrate well that's that's a great
that's a definition that you can get
very easily but if you want to really
learn in depth I type in what is a
carbohydrate read it like I I add the
word read it to my google searches
because then I can kind of get a
conversation that in my opinion this is
this is not the absolute truth please
this is gonna get taken on context and
my life is over but seems like a lot of
reddit people are a little more
intelligent than our basic hey I have an
answer so I'm gonna give it or like you
know on Amazon when it's like hey does
this come with two triple A batteries in
someone responds I don't know what's the
[__] responding for then so you have
the Internet is full of people who don't
actually have an opinion but they're
like well I saw that so I should grunt
at it oh here's my keyboard room so I
think learning how to use the internet
Google just add reddit to the end of
your search that's gonna help you at
least a little bit rights the ship
because it is just the front of the
Internet yeah well nobody it's not you
like your identity is not you you're
just like a just a guy there no one
knows who you are your face isn't even
on there your name's not on there and
you have no incentive but to help these
people and then the upvote download
system allows if you got one person that
has no idea what they're talking about
and nine that they that do know what
they're talking about it that is gonna
get downloaded to hell and you're like
oh this is bad information like these
this these people on this page that
they've sought out the know stuff about
this have decided that this is bad
information so it's at least so you want
to trust that of course yeah I mean I
would trust it more than just the
Wikipedia
definition of whatever you're looking at
I mean that is quite literally the
definition and it's probably good but it
lacks nuance or any ruled application
when anybody can also edit Wikipedia
that's actually not true it's not true
no it's only some pages so it's funny as
I was saying that I was like wait that
seems like a crazy thing to say
dude Wikipedia is actually the [__]
because they have so if you're in
college use Wikipedia don't quote it but
they have footnotes for every single
source where they got these things and
you can get all your sources from
Wikipedia sources for stuff very nice Oh
life hack
don't copy/paste Wikipedia oldest user
sources boom okay done deal yeah it's
great sending kids off to college but I
mean learning how to read research is
hard as [__] but it's super important
because most research is basically
backed by corporations because it's
expensive so if you can find bias in
almost all studies are biased almost all
percentages you see on any supplement
they've worked this data to make it look
like this
so it's [__] so learning how to just
sniff [__] out in your life and
especially in the fitness industry
because there's just no there's not
really an easy way it's just grit
determination and you got to just try
things for yourself and that's hard and
that takes a long time if you don't like
that frustrating and you read a magazine
in in April and it says this thing and
then in March they completely say the
opposite thing and you're like well [__]
weird self contradictory information in
that same magazine
oh yeah the next because the the page
before it is trying to sell their ad and
they have these kind of statistics that
really have nothing to do with the next
page but they kind of look like they do
that's how weird everything is it's all
we all think that like everything that
we're fed is just supposed to be like oh
this is absolute but it's just all
marketing and it's just being sold to us
and categorized and renamed into ways
that make little bite-size yes or noes
to us yeah once you can look at the
world and just see people's motivation
behind selling you things and then look
at the numbers that they're throwing you
like oh you're absolutely full of [__]
like this is so this is just insidious
that you're trying to do this to try to
squeeze money out of people my one of my
favorite things that's happened recently
the game-changers documentary that came
out a lot of people mad about that yeah
well it's just pretty much all
empirically false and just rigged it's
just it's just not it's not a
documentary okay so I saw a little bit
about it
there was someone on Joe Rogan like two
weeks ago Spencer woods yeah it seemed
to clarify a few things for me but do
you have anything else that you want to
add so anybody who has seen this
documentary wants named overtime game
changers game changers on so so that's
something that I think we should
definitely talk about in these things
because just as much as is a lot of us
get fooled by if it's on the news that
must be true like there's a lot of
people who like you know let's take
Trump supporters just to put them all
into a bin like they like they're they
don't realize that hey that's not the
only truth that exists in the world but
I think that we kind of accidentally
think that Netflix is if you think about
it she's oh let's make sure that we're
we're so Netflix isn't the ultimate
truth just so we're clear so let's let's
clarify the documentary census so I
actually didn't really want to pick on
it all the way but there's is a piece of
percentage information in that
documentary that really displays my
point very well so it's um a at leat a
high trained athletes switch to a vegan
diet and in two weeks increased his
output on the battle ropes by 40% no I
think it was as benchpress by 35%
it's okay so let's just break that down
that sounds super good to vacuum-like
like all documentaries that don't have
opposing points like if there's nobody
refuting it in front of you so of course
it sounds great yeah cuz it's just they
kind of place it like it's an argument
against something it's not though no and
it's always so punchy it's like you did
this and then this happened and base all
these great results but no-one's like
well actually this is like there's no
nuance of this it's just exactly what
they want you to hear so if I let's say
i benchpress 300 pounds or 400 pounds
and I increase it by 44 percent in two
weeks I'll be benching over 600 pounds a
little under 600 pounds okay there's you
cannot switch a diet for two weeks and
increase your bench rest by a hundred
and fifty pounds it's not possible
that's just not see they give his
restarting like weights was he just like
some skinny dude no there's an endurance
athlete I believe this one was a weight
lifter but it's just that's just not
true you just can't do that and if you
just are aware of that and look at that
you're like hey that can physically
can't happen it's so easy to be
starstruck by percentages and like oh
they're smart people telling me smart
stuff I'm just gonna
listen to that but if you just take a
step back and just think about it for
any amount of seconds you like that's
not possible there's just no way that
that could happen well but I think also
our Instagram vacation week we hang on
to [__] like that we're like wait two
weeks we can do something like what is
that let's write that down like we have
this super obsession which I mean I've
always been in that same way like when I
was younger I'd always take like like
tons of just random supplements beaten
sold stuff thermogenics up the butt
because I want to like get this resolved
when I lose this weight fast oh please
stop taking those if you're taking those
I haven't for a long time wait actually
while we touched on it though what's bad
about thermogenesis I used to let me
hopefully take them thermogenics are a
stimulant that supposedly increase your
metabolism but your body wants to
regulate itself at a set point so if you
if you take something to increase output
of anything your body's gonna freak out
and try to drive it down so if you have
like a month of having an elevated
metabolism due to stimulants you're
gonna have a rebound from that and
you'll actually have a slower metabolism
after yeah because your body yo-yos all
the time you see with people steroids
so they take steroids their body stops
making testosterone because they're just
getting it somewhere else yeah so it's
like oh you don't need to make any more
yes so they get this rebound that's why
the balls get small mm-hmm they get this
rebound and then when they come off
they're not making any more so they get
real real big and then they get real
small fat and sad just so your body is
just trying to fight everything you're
putting in it to stay in this thing
called homeostasis or just like the the
setpoint or a normal point and that's
rescue everyone yes that's why weight
loss is hard that's why muscle gain is
hard anything other than what you are
right now is hard to get to because it's
your body resists change just in general
well in dude we misinterpret at the time
that these things take like we we
genuinely like we don't understand the
framing of how health works we we think
that like okay I need to get healthy
like so how do I lose you know because
what I'm referencing on like people who
are so overweight that they're like I
know that this is gonna take me so long
but it's you you have to change your
look at how health works like not man
I'm gaining weight so I need to go to
the gym so I can lose that weight and
then once I'm back in 150 pounds then I
could just never work out again and
we'll be good that's
how things work like we need to learn
how everyone everyone in my opinion
should have some sort of athletic
movement stretching walking outside with
no [__] rap music in your headphones
in anything I think that the way that we
see health in the way that we see
getting in shape and the way that we see
diets we either don't want to attack
them or we have the most unrealistic
standards when we approach them that we
either give up or we go for three weeks
and we're like I feel the same and I
feel stressed out now so I'm done I
think that approaching health is
completely needs to be a waste load now
yeah if you're weighing yourself every
day stop yes do wait okay hold up scales
are ridiculous so actually if you have a
good relationship with it incredibly
good empirical evidence on if it's
working or not but if you aren't
exercising and aren't doing anything to
increase your fitness you should stop
playing yourself because it's just a
source of pain yeah if you really think
so think about what the thoughts that
you think when you get on the scale and
it's a bad number and then think about
what why the [__] would that have
anything to do with a number a weight is
just it's a unit of measurement that we
made up like here's a general like if
you're around this age and this way here
but it's really not absolutely like it's
it's asking yourself to get mad at
yourself every day it's just data with
no reference points so your body is made
up of way more than body fat you can
gain and lose up to seven to eight
pounds a day and water and carbohydrates
so when you eat carbs you can store 500
grams in your liver and up to 300 grams
in your muscles and those carries 3
grams of water and then if you're you
know more sodium you're gonna hold our
water and holding water is good by the
way for the most part unless you are
like bloated like water bloating a puffy
face probably like eat some potassium
like eat some but that's a super
short-lived I feel like yeah it just
will flush it like don't get bloated
mixed with with yeah but I see clients
do this whole time like they will weigh
themselves every single day like they'll
go out one night and then they'll weigh
themselves the next morning and they'll
be all up sex their up weight okay but
you just had a meal that's bigger than
usual so you've got fecal matter water
carbs more than you're eating so of
course you're gonna weigh more they're
like oh yeah I was really happy cuz I'm
just I'm getting my weight back down
after I have big meals I'm okay okay
let's do the math on this
so in order to gain one pound of fat you
need to overeat 3,500 calories that's
over three large Big Mac meals with a
large soda that needs to be more than
you're burning anyways so that would
realistically you probably if you're
like a 170 pound adult male with like
average muscle mass you're probably
burning 2,500 calories a day just like
if you move at all so you got to add
that on top of that so now you would
have to be it's like 6,000 calories so
you have to overeat 6000 calories to
gain one single pound so when you see
your weight fluctuate seven pounds okay
that's like 16,000 extra calories
there's no way that's empirically
impossible for you to gain that much
amount of weight in fat so maybe stop
worrying about it yeah it doesn't make
sense we put ourselves through these
weird mental strains I mean I think that
we really need to break out of the way
that the health industry hasn't made us
think and start really taking a step
back and be like wait why am i weighing
this stuff why does that number mean
anything how do I feel how about that
how do I feel
does my the way that my body is in the
way that my health my mental health
affects and works one-on-one with my
body does that equal my lifestyle like
if you're an archer and you love to play
Archer and you liked if I can roll
around on the ground before you take
your shot of the arrow then you're not
gonna have a bodybuilders workout style
you're not gonna have the same exact
diet as someone who works in an office
all day you have to figure out what
works for your [__] lifestyle and
well if they can make you feel like
you're less than and need something
you'll buy stuff that's just like a
capitalist principle idea like oh I'm
less than I don't drive a nice car like
I don't look good enough I got a be a
consumer and buy these things cuz
they're gonna solve my problems it's
funny because well it's actually not
funny a [__] won't there's not gonna
solve your problems like you're you're
going to if you would like to and is it
even a problem in the first place it's
also a good question right well they
they tell us that it's these problem I
have this a lot because I get a lot of
people that I'll message like one-on-one
I mean it gets I do like a little bit of
life coaching to it to some people that
are important to me in in I feel like I
have to say that a lot it's like what
are you what are you saying you're
failing it what are you saying that you
need to make better here
what what what needs to get better you
don't need to get better just change
this thing it's not like you're doing
this thing wrong
I think that yeah yeah I think that that
is a good entryway into you need to not
look at failure like a failed state and
like a teaching opportunity because when
you look at all these things that you do
poorly here and learn way more for them
well then when you succeed so when you
fail you can't feel bad about it you
must take something from this learn a
lesson and then be better later or just
use a tool like your life data they
should be aggregating data on how to
just be a better you and if you don't
take failures like that you're just
gonna suffer but if you do you're gonna
flourish yes so and that's easy with
food all the time people beat themselves
every big meal man that's life it's
gonna happen right like you need to just
be able to navigate your life and just
temper all these things with some nuance
okay just say of course I'm gonna go out
and have a bad meal I mean it's even bad
there's no good foods and bad foods this
is just not what's on my plan and that's
fine no that's okay you know we're not
I'm not gonna get upset about it we're
just gonna get right back to it we're
gonna get right back to what we're doing
and I'm not gonna worry about it because
this brought me joy right I gotta hang
out people I gotta be in a social
setting and that is equally as important
as conquering your fitness goals or
whatever you want to do like there's a
heaven flow to all these things and I
tell people all the time when they're
trying to lose weight or they want to
look some way if what you need to
relinquish in your life to get to this
point like if the told that needs to be
paid if it will bring you more suffering
and less happiness in the end goal maybe
we should set different goals like if
you gotta if you got to give up too many
things like if you like to have a glass
of wine every night I probably don't
recommend it but if that's if that's
what brings you a lot of joy and your
fitness goals don't align with that
maybe you should set your fitness goals
if that's gonna make you less happy hey
yeah there's some push and pull and
these are also things that you can do
long-term like you know what let's give
myself three months of a glass of wine
each night and then at 3 months
let's try six nights a week mm-hmm
rather than seven these little things I
think and we do if we do do pretty
extreme things and that's something that
I I do extreme things because that seems
to work for me like I have a lot of
examples where I'm like a man I read
this audio book and ran 14 miles like
[__] like that doesn't work for
everybody so you have to find what works
for you like sometimes I need to like
just push myself I have friends who need
to be like yes or no black or white on
or off you got to figure out what we're
for you but I think that currency is not
just calories or time or even money I
mean you've got to say like how does
this weigh out to me just living a
healthy life in general mm-hmm you can
apply that to most things - yeah
brilliant just that thought process is
whatever this goal I'm gonna end up at
I'm gonna make me happier than I am now
or bring me more satisfaction rather I
don't really want to say happiness
or am I gonna suffer more than usual to
get here and well I mean what happens
when you get there that's why the end
goal should never be the focal point it
should be the journey there exactly you
can't have control the Engel Canyon well
you cannot but if you control how you
show up in that situation if you just
fall in love with the process which is
like so cliche to say but it's real
you will just Mort you're gonna succeed
more than you would have because you
know it doesn't get you through like a
shitty day when you got to go work out
you like to chicken breast and white
rice oh I wanna have abs in six months
you know it does okay man like this is
how I live this is what I like and I'm
just this is this is what I do this is
me right so if you can just be
internally motivated throughout the day
and then find the little things and all
these things you like and just enjoy all
these little moments that you get to
have throughout the day because focusing
on the end goal you just don't you just
look past your life because you're just
charging towards this thing but if you
can take a step back and enjoy all this
stuff even if it's not necessarily the
most pleasurable thing if you can find
something to enjoy in it you're gonna
get there yeah because what's the point
of getting there if you're you miss the
in-between what's the point the point of
a dance as I say or as Alan Watts says
is to not to get to the other side of
the room but to enjoy the dance in
between you know it's not who is the
fastest dancer and I think that the
consumer based capital society we live
in
really really puts a lot of emphasis on
the end and not a lot of emphasis on the
during or the journey because you're
just accruing whatever you have
resources money well fitness because you
just want to get there I want the big
house I want the fast car with the huge
muscles and you're gonna do whatever you
need to to get there and you're gonna
put your head down but then when you
fail it's a catastrophic
right when you're focusing day-to-day
and you were just living your life and
like being present and all these things
if you fail you just take note of it
okay we're do better tomorrow because
you're not looking at the end just your
being alive you know what what I was
thinking to round out everything we've
kind of just said on the healthiest
thing instead of saying instead of
looking for your end goal instead of
looking for your how do I lose this much
weight in this amount of time how do I
in 30 days how do I be this whatever
what you should do with your health is
say how do I live every day individually
by itself the happiest and healthiest
that I can and that's all like don't you
know it end goals help you direct these
things so maybe determine them at the
beginning okay here's what I'm shooting
for in the end but then let's let that
thing fade away to like cool I'll check
that in six months but for now how do I
have the most healthy overall day how do
I feel the best because if you're going
through you know if you want to have the
best life but you have important
conferences that you need to go speak at
on Tuesday but you're also at the same
time trying to get to be 4% [__] body
fat when you go talk to that conference
you're gonna be a damn idiot because you
are trying to starve yourself to get to
these other goals you have to balance
your goals and see where they fit in
your life and there's nothing wrong
being four percent body fat I mean it's
actually not physically healthy but if
that's what you want and that's gonna
bring you the most joy man don't do it
it's [__] not that girl for you it's
not though dude it might though I mean
is if like if people dude some people
are just conquerors they were percent
body fat they want to just be on to a
body pillow sorry they just want to be
on top of the mountain like like their
whole life is just to be this and this
is what they want the most and then when
we get there that's the ultimate set I
guess so but that's these people it's
definitely their whole life but yeah
there's nothing wrong with that but
that's not for everyone yeah like and I
also think that I don't want to sound
like I'm being too easy on people and
that they should just can't hold onto
their vices because that's what's gonna
make them the happiest right the health
getting getting to the healthy part is
the important part and sometimes that is
curbing your vices and learning how to
live a more moderate lifestyle uh-huh as
well I mean I advise is even try to be
very very very empathetic and very
lenient with people and with and always
meet them where they're at but there is
a certain amount of hey man no matter
what you do this is not gonna be optimal
right it's just not which is hard to
hear I mean you do this very well I feel
like you're a very empathetic person
it's hard to tell people like you're
doing this wrong and I think that you're
doing it wrong because I'm right you
know it's hard to I will I always try to
reassure people on how they are how they
feel and how it's okay where they're at
right now because I never wanted the
point where I'm like I'm right you're
wrong do this I want there has to be
playing this like hey like maybe okay we
know this is behavior maybe it's not
super optional for health maybe let's uh
let's just find a way to maybe temper it
a little bit and slowly slowly change
things a slower you can change things
the better because even on a biological
level like your body just doesn't like
big changes so you can just you know
revert back to a lot of times yes I mean
you get the yo-yo dieting yeah you drop
all your calorie started in this crazy
diet and then you just are so crazed for
food and you've not allowed yourself to
enjoy anything you just have this pen up
like force inside of you then you eat
everything then you feel like [__] and
you failed and now you're depressed now
you've regained all your weight you're
like this is me this is who I am every
time I do it it reaffirms Who I am
instead of looking at like hey man I got
31 days this time I'm gonna get 32 next
time you know things like that we're
never failing that is like a guess
backing up I was just saying you know
doing something wrong it's not doing
wrong either it's again it's never
failing
we got to just keep figuring out what
works for us it's just a lesson it's all
just a lesson you got if you can
navigate your life and look at things
and look at everything like a teaching
lesson like I was talking to my
grandparents who I could not disagree
with more in any to any more extreme
degree and politically in any
ideological way and every time I so for
the last six months I've really really
tried to listen to people I really
disagree with and really hear them out
not necess I don't believe what they do
and I feel like I have a more nuanced
opinion I don't know sounds pretentious
but I genuinely feel like I've thought
more about it and I'm pretty I'm not
concrete in my beliefs but I know that
that end of it is just not not how I
feel but in I need to listen to them so
I can understand how they feel so I can
communicate with people like that better
of course
and then maybe is a huge goal of my life
and then if we can communicate better
then maybe I can
expel some of my ideas and maybe you'll
take them because now we're speaking the
same language I yeah I think that you
know if you think about its kind of what
people like you and that like this is
what this conversation is about I mean I
want I want to figure out how we can
like stop having these stupid
conversations these stupid arguments
that are like hey you guys aren't
actually arguing what you really think
you're arguing someone else's opinion
against someone else's opinion and it's
because you haven't learned the correct
information you haven't you've been told
what you know yes you haven't found it
it found you kind of thing what it has
turned into I mean so our way of truth
has kind of been thrown away truth is
such a hilarious word in the setting
because it's like is there even I need
to find and that's kind of the problem
as well but uncovering that is is it's a
shaky reality like it really is you know
there's a lot of people that if they
really dope into that question like what
is truth and they started writing it
down and they started exploring like
maybe maybe some wormholes on YouTube
it's super fun but there's a lot of
people who it's like I don't think would
be mentally stable afterwards almost no
no probably not but it doesn't mean you
shouldn't try though right I really
think that if anyone listening wants to
have just a more round worldview or
sound worldview rather mm-hm
just start researching about philosophy
philosophy has always been kind of
guarded behind oh this is for the
aristocrats is for the educated people a
philosophy is for the working folk the
average man yes like this is a way for
you to make a cohesive worldview and
then have deductive reasoning and look
at things from a bunch of sides from a
bunch of opinions and then find out how
you really feel and then be able to
temper results so when other people are
talking to you you can speak with more
nuance and I feel like that is what we
are completely devoid of now because no
one everyone is so dogmatic this is what
I believe I'm team this and anything
that you say because you're on my team
is just it just immediately shut down
yeah because I'm team this it means that
you are team this so whatever you say I
already know that you're team that so it
doesn't matter they just completely
identify with this and they can do no
wrong like all their beliefs are
completely concrete and sound and that
lack of flexibility allows for no nuance
and it also doesn't allow people to
actually talk to each other as peers
like it like would like a back and forth
it's not a conversation we're talking at
each other not with each other yeah dude
it kind of if you know if you think
about it I was thinking about I really
think about the word community a lot you
think about how community has changed
you know obviously through technology
but just through time just through
culture community is super different now
because of the internet I think that
that listening to other people's
opinions and fighting people's fighting
people's opinions versus yours we're
fighting people in China versus our
opinions over here and it's like man
everything is so it's so different that
it's dissolving the word community we're
getting confused about what community
means I think that it's gonna be kind of
important I think like the small town
community is going to be a little bit
rebirthed
and I think that it's super important I
think that instead of saying you know
I'm all for like globalization is not
not the word that I want to in that
sense with but I think that we should I
think I I do see you know in in a future
I do see us as being I don't know I
guess I'd like to daydream about us
being like earth like we are the species
of Earth rather than just like all these
subdivisions but I think that what's
happening with technology what's
happening with all this marketing with
all this lying to us with all this what
the [__] is happening in all the world
of social media and technology is
dissolving communities and I let's just
touch more on that let's let's
roundabout that what's your opinion
there on communities in how it's been
changed and a little bit taken from us
like in accordance to the Internet yes
well so ironically the most powerful
tool for communication is to evolve
communication to quite a large degree
like you don't we did that it's allowed
us to just split into our little corners
where everyone agrees with us and then
we just build more radical ideas and we
use different language so now we can't
communicate with other people
so we've now create a language but
language barrier inside of our own
language that we both speak but we're
really connected but we're really
connected but are we really no we're not
and you can never understand attention
either because people can't emot-- they
can't use facial expressions so you
can't tell people are attacking you so
like
one person asks you a question and you
feel like it's snide and it's it's a
front and they don't want to know the
answer they're just attacking you you
will always respond to this like it's an
attack even if somebody's actually
asking you this question so this just
you get one bad egg and now all these
people are just repelling each other
because any genuine way that people try
to communicate from another side is
looked at as an attack because someone
already did that so your defenses are
always up right and sometimes we're
fighting things were like what are you
talking about I didn't even know that
situation existed so of course I'm not
prepared to fight against it of course
I'm not prepared to posture against it
and then again posturing even just
getting put to where you have to posture
to defend yourself against an idea that
you've never had what the [__] is up
with that
yes that rips us apart it's unfortunate
and we're also looking at these people
like non people right because we don't
even use this line same language anymore
we'd be arguing about the same [__] we
probably all the same problems he's your
[__] neighbors right you know you're
fighting them on Twitter I mean not
quite literally but it might as well be
like these are just regular people like
we're all suffering to some degree like
society is alway affion us unless we are
billionaires like we are just all eaten
dicks so I don't know that was just the
one but I'm sorry no it's okay said
dicks and I laughed as an immature I
think that communities men are being
ripped away from us and I think I was
thinking of this weird it's I have this
bad habit of throwing analogies places
where they don't belong which is hard to
solve problems there but I was thinking
about I like comparing humans to Apes
all the time and so I think we've talked
about this before we talked about like
if you imagine a phone being a pacifier
like if you so take it take a pacifier
out of a two-year-olds mouth they're
gonna cry like I say I want it back this
is the same like you want to be safe in
the cave this is evolution this is how
we work right well we now have the cell
phones as the same thing as the pacifier
but anyway so I was thinking of an ape
imagine an ape with a cell phone and
then you give a [__] lion in Africa a
cell phone and now they can talk cool
communication we're all connected but
they're having different conversations
they don't speak the same [__]
language they're different species this
is what's happening like yeah we're all
humans yes we are all one
and this is super complicated if I can
paragraph there to go into but I think
that we have so many different levels of
intelligence background culture we
shouldn't just be like this is your
community now talk up with this apes and
lions on cell phones yeah dude it's a
it's a massive problem
I really think I'm tired of fighting
with people actually I don't really
fight with people when I'm really tired
of watching other people fight about
stuff so I probably agree on yeah if
they were if they were face to face in
there was just one person who'd be like
hey guys come on like let's just think
about you didn't really mean that if
there was like one moderator and people
are face to face a majority of these
things that people arguing about on the
internet and on the news and [__] would
go away yeah well I think the just
talking heads with corporate agendas
telling you what to think and be angry
at other people is really just a big
ploy to not make you think about how
there's a just a whole overarching
system that is [__] all of us mm-hmm
I mean cuz that's just really what's
happening like if we if if corporations
can make us mad at each other we're
gonna buy more stuff and not question
anything right but if we get to be mad
at the 1% if we can actually like the
the most powerful thing any government
could do that it's going to do
tyrannical things is put the people
against each other right and not
together dude it just we're just letting
it happen to and the problem is we pick
teams and then we listen to people talk
who are just very radical and when we
take their ideas and then we spit them
out each other and we don't there's no
you're not talking to this person to
talk to them you're talking to them to
posture and you want to win you don't
want to talk right and winning is not
helpful your winning is the craziest
concept that's what all I mean cap it's
just a result of capitalism but it's
it's we think that conversations and
debates or maybe we think that every
conversation is a debate and it needs to
be won and it's like dude these are
people in your real life community
you're fighting this fake community that
the internet just told you that you're
in but then you get so caught up in that
that you forget like oh [__] oh yeah I
have a real life like oh yeah like I
have neighbors who actually exist you
know more than
Republicans or Democrats like we we get
this constant ship fed to us on the news
and all the stuff that it keeps us
locked in to these terrible positions
and we think that's our personalities
tribalism [__] yes it's so easy to flex
to on people like for the for people
that want this to be like that it's so
easy to enact because it's just a
natural state of being it requires a lot
of extra thought to deny the tribal
behavior and we all have a little bit of
it like I'm I'm on some teams I am oh
yeah I'm just looking so very yeah see
that's I'm looking for them every day to
make sure that's like oh this one's cool
this one's awesome I love this one this
is me bunch of my dumb friends [__]
hanging out and playing super smash
president Rincon beer that's a cool
tribalist thing that I do but like you
got to watch out for these other areas
like oh how it's kind of acting a fool
that's gonna act an AP
right you know you get that groupthink
and then all of a sudden you get a bunch
people holding tiki torches marching in
DC and there just happens that fast dude
once you get that big group thing people
start doing really radical stuff crowds
have layers even we've touched on that
earlier like I don't know man
people act differently when they're in
crowds and I think that this false like
when you're talking [__] about
Republicans on your Facebook you think
that you have all of the Democrats
behind your back but you're actually
just look like a [__] you look like
an [__] so man I I don't know I mean
I guess I can't say that that's not
always and just because you're talking
about again let me clarify just because
you're talking about these things or
political doesn't mean that you're an
idiot but the political whole race is
just it's been managed it's way worse
than oh if you're in the whole thing and
not outside of it I think you might have
trouble seeing how messed up it is and
how the thoughts that you're throwing if
these other people aren't yours you know
like it kind of makes me mad frankly you
know there's people that I love who are
their thoughts are what they've read on
the internet like they're doing things
that I know them to their soul I know
them in their heart and they're doing
things that don't don't interact there
and I'm like dude I know you I know who
you are and I just think it's unfair
it's it's not fair I think that a good
care for that is obviously taking care
of your mental health but just do don't
like watching the news 24 hour news all
the time at your work or at your place
of business at your home is not healthy
you don't need 24-hour news it's not
news it's feeding you stuff she's
getting mad yeah here's on my favorite
examples of this
so stereotypically Republicans are
religious okay the Bible is a book that
says - like there's like a welfare state
and to help other people and be very
charitable and just be very nice to
people and all these people are people
and we should treat them as such they're
no better or worse than you but all
their political opinions do not align
with this book so you've got these two
pillars of who you are and they're just
as contradictory they physically can be
it's like I can't make a concurrent
worldview for you like I don't know what
you believe because it's all
contradictory so I literally can't even
talk to you like it there isn't at no
point in time where I can ever
extrapolate your worldview because it's
just not well it's not one you just
doesn't make sense so I can never meet
you anywhere and it's very hard well how
do people realize that they're doing
this like they don't this is the biggest
thing is I think that what we're
discovering a lot of times is like when
you point it out they feel attacked you
know I mean there's gotta be you know
that's something that a podcast like
this is great because I want to work on
ways that we can have these
conversations and help people not just
talk [__] about them of course obviously
so I'm always trying to like I wasn't
trying to poke fun that's just something
that I've noticed you know you have you
have - no no no I just wanted to be
clear on my end just I'm not just trying
to like throw everybody who deals with
politics into some sort of bin I just
think that I want to make sure you and I
know what subject were talking on and I
want to make sure that a listener knows
also this no I just think but but your
huge thing that I do notice that is
going to be important is podcast like
this stuff like this people who what I
have noticed is a lot of people talking
about the right is really loud and the
left is [__] crazy like the in these
are just broad that's a left the extreme
left or whatever well that's what's like
happening those are like the squeakiest
wheels right
those are the ones that get the
attention so we think that like that is
the left and that is the right but like
there's also people who are just like
I'm just trying to live and like I don't
care about any of that but like let's
figure out what that what the best way
of doing all these things is so what
I've been hearing though is that a lot
of people who are maybe sort of left or
maybe like they don't care about all the
the fanatics they're just trying to like
live but but they don't have
conversations like this yes I don't
we're afraid to have opinions it's what
I'm trying to narrow down to and if you
think about it everybody's super afraid
to have opinions I was looking this
morning on my Instagram which I've been
all over again lately I'm told I can
addicted to it again because I've been
releasing this podcast I gotta watch
myself here but I was looking at my post
and I was like I haven't ever actually
deleted post like I noticed the last
couple years people they like redo their
life they like delete all their old
posts and they just start with like the
most recent or they like only delete
like one a year or something I don't
know which is cool whatever but I was
looking at I have 669 posts I'm like man
so I'm starting this podcast now I'm
saying I'm representing this thing and I
was like man people couldn't go back
through and look at me being a [__]
like maybe I wonder what the terminology
I've seen on Facebook my memories I've
I've I've said ni GGA on Facebook when I
was I was talking I was writing rap
lyrics or whatever they weren't mine I
was just repeating them from Kid Cudi
but I saw that and I was like oh my god
like I would be probably like in trouble
for saying these sort of things but I
mean I forgot what I was what I was
pinpointing to that but I just think
that not being able to make mistakes and
not being able to talk out loud is
making people not say anything at all so
I want to again like we started with
this I'm gonna fail out loud like I've
been a dork on my social media I might
have said weird things maybe in any of
my guests have like I think that not
being afraid of someone trying to like
bring you down or like hurt you or like
insult you or ruin your life or hurt
your opinion has made a lot of people
not say a [__] thing so I don't know
I think that people need to stand up a
little more and be a little braver and
take a little more courage and start
more podcasts and and start speaking up
about the things that like they think
needs heal to start offering ways to
heal them so the
I guess that's kind of what we're doing
here yeah man start talking to your
neighbors to see what their problems
alright
maybe those [__] we got him
like why are we gonna spurn the people
who live in our community so bad like
we're so worried about big stuff but
like hey maybe your old neighbor is just
not eating because no one's taking care
of them like you know just we need to
help these people these are just people
just because they don't believe what you
believe
hmm I mean and that's the thing is we
think that we need to solve all these
other big great big problems about like
all these things we out of our control
but our house is not in order
you know like we I think that if we all
stop looking out here for things to
solve as much and start kind of just
narrowing it down a little bit like what
can we solve here I'm like what can I
solve in my community so I'm starting to
bring in people around me you know and
and you're doing the same you're like
what okay like I have a lot of
information maybe I don't want to sit
there and argue with much dudes who
think they have more information on
[__] rabbit but what I can do is I
can offer people who have zero - from
that zero mark or people who don't know
very much about fitness whatever it is I
can definitely help them my community
people listen to what I'm saying on
whatever so this harkens back I'm just
gonna bring it back to not being afraid
to say something stupid or fail and you
just need to have good intentions like
if you obviously have really good
intentions with things and then you do
fail or you do mess up and you don't say
something correctly or you're wrong
which I reserve every right to be wrong
by the way if I'm ever wrong tell me go
ahead I would love to talk about it
right here I got it but if you just have
because a lot of people just don't have
good intentions in the first place a lot
of bad faith stuff that's happening
right now like people are just making
points in bad faith just to be a
[__] but if you genuinely really
just want to help and you're gonna be
wrong I feel like the the scrutiny and
the criticism is just not gonna come and
also once people see that you just rock
to the beat of your own drum said hey
there knocking I'm not gonna bend the
knee to anyone I will tell you yeah I
was wrong we could talk about it but I'm
gonna just keep doing what I'm doing and
I'm not gonna change who I am because
you pointed out that I was wrong once
yes I'm finally big an individual who's
wrong in your opinion like super fine
with that people just need to stand with
themselves more how many people need to
have better intentions with a lot of
things as well but you just need to
trust yourself and grow from all these
things and just not be scared to put
your neck out because in order to
progress and see the people around you
progress and you need to talk to each
other and you do because sometimes you
have bad opinions and your friends if
you really trust them and they have good
opinions they'll tell you when you're
wrong mm-hmm that's how we learned if
you never get to expose any of your
ideas and see them falsified in front of
other people right you're in a bad
opinions that's something that you you
and I talked about a lot like you you
have a pretty good solid group of
friends that you're able to have like
intellectual conversations you also are
able to have like the the friendly manly
banter with each other - that's
something that like I've told you like I
I don't do very well like I've never
been I was raised in a household with a
lot of women I think that I've just made
me a sensitive dude like a lot of I
never really understood as I was growing
up like the punch in your as well punch
in your buddy and in like the the making
fun of people thing but it's funny
people who know me kind of understand
that about me and they don't really you
know like my friends make you know like
it's all this this light-hearted thing
but I'm again back to your friend group
I think that that's super important like
can you talk a little bit about how how
that friend group meant be different
from from someone else's oh so we just
don't poop on each other at all Oh cover
like we actually that I think that that
manly banter we just got to see caveman
style like if they can hold up like if
they're gonna be strong enough to help
you survive but we've ever owned that
and you got to hype each other up
because the world's hard and it's scary
and people kind of poop on you so you
better type your friends up but then we
also I spent a lot of time with my
brother and his best friend just talking
about philosophical points like Phillip
philosophy is easily my favorite thing
to talk about and I spend probably six
seven hours a week just discussing
things and that goes to politics as well
because it's very generally applicable
but this freedom of thought and speech
has allowed me to develop a better or a
more coherent worldview and what I
believe and what I don't believe in like
ethical state and how I feel about other
people how I treat other people and it's
allowed me to grow a lot so if you can
find other people that are willing to
just discuss things with you and bounce
ideas and do some research you're gonna
grow a lot as a person and I personally
have I've changed so much in the last
year just from just having extremely
long-form conversations about very very
abstract ideas
well I do it because it's cool because
it becomes this you start out of the
conversation with me with an idea versus
you with an idea and then before you
know it if you're doing it correctly
it's the ideas that are battling each
other and sometimes you can make a third
super idea out of like the intellect
that you just put together and I think
that philosophy why is that it's like
like the gold crown that's like what you
want and it's for me it's a oh man it's
you know we talked about the same a lot
of the same stuff but diving into
philosophy and then being able to take
the things you've learned throw them at
the wall of someone else that's of
something else that somebody else
learned and then together come up with
honestly sometimes it seems like an
original idea original like what if this
is actually what's happening here what
if this is what might happen next what
if this is what this person is doing
what if this is overarching what's
happening here on earth like whatever
which is super exciting and it's you'll
notice that those conversations fly by
and they're so fun and you notice you
don't to stop and think these are the
type of things that you can replace a
lot of us you know we go to Applebee's
and we just talk [__] about people in
our hometown right we just gossip we
just pull up social media hey have you
seen this newest article I'm so sick of
talking about what recently happened
it's starting to drive me crazy I think
I'm gonna lose my mind so not that
everybody has to just talk about
philosophy all the time right but I'm
willing to bet that you're your friend
group regardless of who they are or one
of your friend groups has some interest
in a lot of the [__] that you're like
secretly interested about like bring it
up you know talk more about in-depth
stuff not about the people nearest to
you I almost never find myself talking
about small things with my friends ever
when we sit down it's always about baby
because you live big weights yes of
course what do you mean big stuff what
do you mean big abstract ideas so like
nothing concrete and now like he said
she said it's like more of a we're
talking about concepts and I'm talking
about just a big ideas that don't have
an answer and it's just a you get a form
your opinions with someone else there
and if you have something that's like
hey if they really are like comfortable
with you and you go comfort with each
other and they rebuttal something you
say because you're not arguing you're
discussing like if they're like yeah
maybe this point you made this is a
fallacy in it and like this is how I
think about it and you're like okay
right so you learn something and you
temper your worldview and then as you
slowly have a more
solid view of how you feel about ethics
philosophy all these like big questions
you can just navigate your life better
because you have a set of ground rules
like this is how I feel about things and
this is how I'm going to look at people
and just if you don't ever have these
conversations you're just gonna have
this a jumbled mess of a worldview where
you just don't treat people and do
things in a very coherent fashion and
you just kind of act emotionally and
wildly mm-hmm but if you can Center your
beliefs and your thoughts around just a
couple principles or things that you
believe to be true in the world and you
can navigate it better I personally
think III agree too I think that also
with that never making any of them too
Stern me personally I'm a seeker of
novelty I like just different stuff I
like remaining and disbelief at all
times I like letting someone I like them
so in the heat of a conference like if
you were a witch like if you're like a
sorcerer and you're like man like this
is what I do for a living like I promise
you on the sorcerer I'm not gonna invite
you over to my podcast and be like I
think you're a [__] liar prove to me
that your sorcerer I'm gonna say like
wait what that's instant like you know
in and I'm being sincere like I
generally want to know like what do you
believe can you make me try to maybe
believe it and I don't have to walk away
and say I believe it or not I can be
like wow that was a crazy experience as
far as my life goes man I just want to
experience the most incredible awesome
things ever in so many people if you
just shut up about your own opinions or
your own whatever and you just let them
tell you what they think your life can
be so awesome you're like whoa and you
could take little bits and pieces this
morning actually I'm something new to me
I'm just exploring like a lot of
different stuff spiritually so though I
did it yesterday as well but this
morning I saged the room and I put like
a con on YouTube that smudging whatever
and I I was like let instead of just
doing this in like standing Magglio so
what's gonna happen hmm I really let
myself dive into this experience like I
knew that a lot of people it's a very
ritualistic experience for them and so I
said let's let's do this you know like
so I put on the correct music some music
that I like that that was associated
with it I looked up some like you know
chants or prayers to say while doing it
and I really generally had like I
I did it by myself down here and I did
the smudging and I said the the mantras
in afterwards I went up to Shelly and I
it's telling her I was like you know
like I feel kind of silly in a way I do
because I know that like at the root
like I've never done anything except if
I'm not Cherokee and I don't know what
or that might be a super Daffy thing to
say there but um I will say that
allowing myself to experience that whole
experience as a human and really just
let myself say what if in remain in
disbelief like this isn't exactly what I
know but I don't really want to
experience this thing if I go into every
conversation in every situation like
that my life seems to be just this
beautiful unraveling wonderful joy map
you know so I think you do the same I
think you you remain in disbelief
III think that yeah yeah yeah I think
you you closely do the same yeah I'm
extremely skeptical but I I'm always
there to listen yeah because even if
somebody is saying something that is
very not true just like you know what's
false uh-huh you at least learn
something you either strengthen your own
worldview or you were learning something
about theirs and you can just one you
collect data on people and it's just
nice and it's nice to know more things
and you communicate better with more
people and then maybe you can trade
ideas better if you can meet them
somewhere I've been really trying to be
the sound observer I really enjoy
talking I usually dominate most rooms
that I'm in I just just speak a lot so
I've over Thanksgiving I try to say as
few words as possible and actually
learned a lot of things yeah and I mean
just like small things about people like
how I'm actually extremely uncomfortable
sometimes right like no if you I'm not
talking and now there's some silence
well I mean it's just I was in a room of
people that I just really really
disagree with in a lot of ways and it
was just very they just lived their life
in such a opposite way that I do and
just watching them just like behave
together and talk it was just so odd
because I'm usually just dominating the
room so of course I would never notice
that but I think that people need to
start listening more and talking less
hmm me first I need to do that
definitely and I've been working very
hard on it right no I mean that's
something that I noticed with this
podcast inevitably like I'm like
man you [__] interrupt to everybody
like all these thing you know we of
course you're older it's critical when
you listen to these things but it's
something that I'm a con man I thought I
was a good listener but now I'm actually
right I'm not just assuming I'm just
like oh I'm a good loser I'm actually
taking a step back and I'm listening to
myself on any podcast I'm like oh I
thought that I was a better listener
than I was there is times where I just
get too goddamn excited and I interrupt
that person across the table from me so
it's funny like noticing what you do but
also noticing what you don't do when you
just sit there and let someone else talk
but but I also think that something that
that I individually have trouble with
that I that I work on is when I am in
those rooms when I am I'm someone who
values my time now more than ever
sometimes I'll sit there and silence and
I'm like there's so many other things
that I could be doing right now that I
it's as easy as getting up and leaving
this room and going to my home and
picking up the book that I love I could
be spending this hour right here doing
something that I love instead of
listening to someone who I completely
disagree with how could you help me with
some advice here and how do I practice
self-love in this or not not self-love
but yeah self-love but love and patience
and so how do I remain in these
conversations where I made am I trying
to contribute but instead of just
sitting here being like man like this
person's dumb and and I wish that I was
doing this thing that I really want like
how can I enjoy my life when I am these
situations like let's say a holiday
event for for example this isn't a
personal experience but just say anybody
has a holiday event they're listening to
people that they don't really want to
listen to you how do they to sit there
not just be annoyed I this might be a
little dehumanizing but I really like to
look at all circumstances like this is a
utilitarian like from a utilitarian
aspect as I'm just collecting data on
how people feel that I don't agree with
mmm and maybe you can learn something
from that I mean it's like a social
experiment like let's just see
let's just see what these people are
going to say like this is something I
don't get here and it's important to
hear that
and whether you think it's completely
false or not it's just good to listen
and maybe you can if you can learn
anything from and it's helpful yeah I
think battling everything that you think
is false will leave you quite exhausted
I think that that just just sitting
there and let people have their
conversation this is pretty important
but it is
it's frustrating the hard sometimes to
know start thinking about stuff that's
important start thinking about so what
do you mean by start thinking about
sound just stop barreling through your
life and just experiencing things and I
had in a headlong fashion like a
cannonball the habits like just take
step back look at stuff question
everything like why am I doing this why
these people do this why do they feel
this way they come and give me an
example in your life like what do you
stop in your tracks
I guess it's that's a good question I
have a couple that I do I have a couple
that I so for example I started write it
with my left hand and you'd be surprised
at how often you go you reach for a door
handle with your right hand you don't
think about reaching for don't handle
you when you say I'm gonna get inside
the house you just walk inside the house
right but slowing down even these little
things I started using my left hand it
started noticing like oh I do this thing
in this way what even small things like
that but just observing what you do and
look at a house I look like after you
say something if you're mad like wait
what just happened to get me mad was am
i red in the face because I'm just
yelling at someone that's kind of weird
do you have any other things that you
that you do that are kind of like that
just consciously try to observe people
and the situations around me and when
people are saying things that I just
don't think are true I like to think
about why they're saying that nothing
not instead of fighting the truth yes
just like how did they come to this
conclusion and that helps a lot for you
not to be angry at this person because
it just humanizes them to some degree
well and it's just like little habits
that you have if you could just take
note of them like hey why do I do this
like is this something that is helpful
for me yeah you just do a bunch of [__]
that's not helpful for you I mean I do
I've got terrible habits we do a lot of
stuff that's not helpful for us yeah but
you have to add that little flag in the
ground and just just by noticing is the
thing I have this um I upload a video to
YouTube two days ago actually that was
on the end
it was on the oh yeah it was on the Mays
so it was not kind of on or no not on
maison sand sorry so I have this story
where me and my friend will hide there
we were walking through may have already
mentioned this to you we are walking in
the sand and we're having conversation
good conversation about philosophy or
something that's awesome I loved it
but we started like picking up speed
because you know when you're walking
through sand it's just like trudging and
it's come hard and you kind of just walk
like a dummy and start walking fast
we kept noticing that as we're having
conversation he would be like oh wait
slow down we would start kind of like
falling into the sand like you're kind
of like you're not really having your
own slow momentum of walking right
you're kind of like this step is just to
catch yourself because that last step
was kind of sketchy so you're you're
leading forward right you're leaning
forward into your life you're having
this conversation bla bla you're going
and you're walking on the beach and then
once in a while I'll do what my friend
will hide this and he's like wait hold
on slow down and it's funny because like
my posture would change I would stop
leaning forward I wouldn't look back and
put my chest out my arms back and it's
like it almost stopped me like oh yeah
let's let's walk slowly in this on this
sandy beach cuz I'm I'm having a
conversation with my friend it's a
beautiful day we've had a couple drinks
we've had a smoke like it was a
wonderful time but we kept getting so
caught up in like the momentum of what
we were talking about that it pulled us
out of the present moment so you got to
be in the present moment having
conversations about these intricate
subjects not being these intricate
subjects fighting each other right so I
think a lot of the times we accidentally
tried to fight the truth or try to prove
to the other person what the truth is
rather than learn about their truth and
then teach them about your truth and see
how that works out together you know
just slow down a little [__] this slow
down pick your head up when you're
walking to supplement the ground yeah
the hunched shoulders staring at the
ground you know there's a whole world
once you look at it so this is that's
something that honestly that's one of
the more huge things which I don't want
to dive into now but next podcast we can
mention on is posture posture is
something you have wonderful posture and
I remember a compliment you gave me you
hadn't seen me for quite a while and I
was doing better in you saw me you liked
me
you see gave me a compliment about it
because my posture was not good before
and I was like I didn't I was very
depressed like it was hard to deal with
but it's funny like now that I'm not
depressed my posture has regained but I
I will say that I actively work on my
posture every day and it's something
that I think really is there's there's
some science behind like the depression
part of that if I can help so there is
one of my biggest pet peeves and all
people and how is bad posture because
it's just as like such a physical
embodiment of a lack of confidence and
just like you're just hiding from the
world right it's something you can
change then just stand up like open up
to the world look at things and it just
it's ours it's just not aesthetically
pleasing either and I know what's bad
for you too
like as a trainer that's my biggest
thing is just sit up right and well so
so something that I had to start doing
it like when I was in private like so
every time that you're in your car when
you're in all these location cuz
sometimes you know when you're if you're
not a confident person if you if you're
thinking about killing yourself and
you're walking across the bridge you're
not going to put my chest out stand up
straight but you're gonna be like but
but I will say that will eventually come
and on that bridge as you're walking
you're not gonna be thinking I want to
kill myself if you just continually feed
yourself with good thoughts right so
when you're by yourself when you're home
and you're working there's nobody around
and you can be a little bit more
confident than in public you give
yourself like oh hey let's fix your
posture alright good job buddy and just
you noticing reward yourself for
noticing oh shoot cool I thought about
the posture three times a day good job
today
good job Frank you're awesome Frank cool
and then those things add up and then
also in public you can start walking so
posture crazy important I'm huge fan
posture I wanna talk more about it but
you're gonna feel silly poking your
chest out like I probably looked silly
but oh yeah I don't care it's better for
me okay well who cares wait so your life
is it's more important for someone to
think that you look silly then for you
to care about your life like this so
that's what you're making a choice if
you are saying I don't want to do that
because I'm cuz it looks silly you're
making a choice to let someone else
choose your own posture for you and in
turn that stuff really does affect your
physiology in your biology its posture
man there's a good fit in school to
start with just work on your posture for
a month
I'm teasing you just stand all day man
like might as well roll your shoulders
back pick it up whenever you feel like
it what's your is is that kind of years
because I have like a couple little
cliques that I do that will end here but
I have a couple things that I'm like
okay when I think of that that gives me
posture is that yours like look up well
your roll your shoulders back is that
the little shoulder blades in your back
pocket real talk and then put tuck your
hips under your body so you get this
butt wink you know like that in the
Instagram fit girl but things and their
spot their lower back is like really
winked out right yeah that looks super
good but it's actually just horrible for
your posture so if you look at your hips
diaphragm and then tongue as like all
bolts all right if they aren't aligning
with each other your postures off so
your hips need to be directly on your
diaphragm and your your tongue needs to
be directly above your diaphragm right
and then roll your shoulders back in
line with your ears so you're standing
perfectly vertical right yeah it's so
it's funny when you think about these
little thing you again you realize how
often you don't think about them like
how often do you think about your
posture listener probably never
it's either my posture sucks or I need
to work on my posture it's the most but
if you it start inserting into your day
like two times a day three times a day
four times a day a hundred times a day
all these little like oh fix your
posture so you know hard over your head
was like head over pelvis or something
there's like me and I like lifting with
my back body or grounding with my back
body lifting with my front that's
something that I say to myself I got
that from yoga with Adriene who that's
my girl
she's on YouTube that's actually a good
one there's 30 days of yoga that you can
do and they're not interesting credibly
difficult they're free they're 20
minutes and those helped with my posture
yeah I think just having these little
phrases in your head to help with
posture I think that's a great place to
start that's one step towards being
mindful so if you want to be healthy I
mean this is this this is a place where
I will want to do anything to help
people be healthy mentally physically
anything so start there you know and
you're awesome listener I love you
heaven yeah you are awesome listener
wherever you're at in your car this is
Jacob Ryan's and my friend Spencer Hicks
we sincerely mean and we open
we hope you have a wonderful rest of
your day this is the end of junkie I
love podcasts I'll see you later bye
you